Loh Sheng Yang, Michael

Blk 612A Tampines North Drive 1, Singapore 521612 +65 97986543

michaellohsy@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub

Summary

Highly motivated senior software engineer with extensive experience working on different technologies. A team player with great communication skills who possesses excellent analytical and trouble shooting capabilities. A quick learner with a passion for learning new technologies.

Education

National University of Singapore (NUS)

Bachelor in Computer Engineering [Hons]

Singapore *Aug. 2009 - May. 2013*

Work Experience

Funding Societies

Singapore

Senior Software Engineer

Sep 2019 - Present

- Designed and implemented a service to provision Virtual Credit Cards to Singapore SMEs
 - * Integrated with 3rd Party Vendor for user, wallet and card provisioning.
 - * Developed webhooks to authorize or reject transactions in a timely manner.
 - * Scheduled monthly jobs to generate and send statements to card owners.
- Redesigned and automated an application registration process, which reduced the time taken to modify or launch a new application from weeks to minutes.
- Built and launched Buy Now Pay Later (BNPL) in Indonesia, which is offered on various e-commerce platforms and has more than 50,000 applications so far.
- Worked on various new features and work flows for trade finance SaaS platform which serves SMEs across 5 different countries.

Plunify Singapore

Senior Software Engineer

May 2016- Sep 2019

- Main developer for Web and Cloud platform involving new architecture and legacy code.
 - * Launching of AWS cloud instances for FPGA chip optimization.
 - * Developed credits and cloud instance management platform.
 - * Integrated payment and OAuth services for web application.
- Developed and integrated desktop GUI application with cloud platform.
- Created machine learning algorithms which reduced FPGA chip optimization times by 20%.
- Performed data visualization and analysis of FPGA data to gain insights into FPGA optimization.

Bioinformatics Institute

Singapore

Software Developer

Aug 2013 - Apr 2016

- Implemented a novel microscopy screening algorithm and helped reduce acquisition time by 40%.
- Performed image registration on biomedical image slices for drug analysis.
- Developed image processing algorithms and software for fly specie detection with 99% accuracy.
- Analysed and provided machine learning solutions for FPGA timing and optimization problems.

Skills

Languages: Javascript, Go, Java, C++, Python, R, PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS

Libraries/Frameworks: NodeJS, Git, JQuery, Angular, AWS

Certifications: AWS Certified Developer